# Gregory Wall Junior Software Developer

London | 07772 086 472 | glawall217@gmail.com

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### **PROFILE**

A motivated software developer where after over five years in the tech industry in operational roles, I transitioned into software development. I completed the Northcoders' Software Development Bootcamp where I acquired essential skills in full-stack web development, particularly in JavaScript, React and Node.js, as well as gained experience with various other technologies, libraries, and frameworks. I have worked on full-stack web applications, both independently and as part of small teams, applying agile methodologies and best coding practices. I'm currently working as a freelance junior software developer for small businesses, and <u>you can view my portfolio here</u>. I am currently learning Python and I am eager to pick up new languages and develop further.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python (currently learning)

Back-end: SQL, PSQL, Seeding, Migrations

Front-end: HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Lighthouse and other accessibility tools

Methodologies: TDD, Jest, Supertest, Paired programming, technical communication, SDL, Agile, Waterfall and SCRUM,

RESTful APIS, Database Design, Responsive Design

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### Freelance Software Developer - Various Companies | October 2024 - Present

- <u>Launchpad</u>: Designed and created a bespoke Events Management system for a community group, utilising JavaScript, Node.js, CSS, Google Calendar API, and Google OAuth. Demo site here. *Login Details here.*
- Rose Fish Bar Currently creating a static HTML website for a local business, in the design phase.
- <u>Defendapack</u> Currently designing a full web application redesign and implementation for a packaging and distribution company. Will be using JavaScript, Stripe, Google & Apple Pay, MongoDB and React.

#### Trainee Software Developer - Northcoders | March - June 2024

- Completed a 13-week full-stack web development bootcamp taught through daily sprints and team projects.
- Designed and implemented a full-stack solo-project web application Relay a reddit style news application.
  - JavaScript, Node.js, CSS, React, PSQL
- Adhering to agile practices created and deployed <u>Good Neighbour</u> A community-focused web application that connects people who need help with those who can provide it.
  - TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, CSS, React, PSQL, Google Maps Implementation. Login Details here.

## People Operations Manager - Pollinate International (FinTech) | May 2020 - December 2023

- Managed onboarding process for 150+ employees and contractors, enhancing the overall employee journey.
- Acquired UK Skilled Sponsorship Licence and facilitated Worker Visas for staff.
- Supported ISO27001 certification and served as a HR business partner for organizational leadership.
- Led the annual Employee Engagement survey initiatives, presenting actionable plans to C-suite executive.

## HR Analyst - Grayce (Contracted to Pollinate International, May 2018 – May 2020

- Collaborated with HR Director to establish Pollinate's employee value proposition and brand framework.
- Implemented HR functions, policies, and key documentation to align with banking standards.
- Sourced and integrated essential HR systems such as HRIS and engagement platforms.

#### Work Placement Officer - ADC College | March 2017 - May 2018

- Developed partnerships for work experience placements by researching and converting leads.
- Trained staff and mentored students to enhance their overall experience, ensuring effective responses to feedback.

## **EDUCATION**

M.A World Heritage Management and Cultural Projects for Development (Distinction)

International Training Centre UN, University of Turin, UNESCO (October 2015 – October 2016)

BA (Hons) History and Philosophy, 2:1

University of Sheffield (September 2011 – June 2014)